Guide to the Women's Refugee Commission Records, 1979-2020; 1979-ongoing, bulk 1989-2011 RL.01405
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Materials and Publications Series, 8 boxes
  - Immigration Court guide (Box 7)
  - Fuel efficient stoves, Darfur, 2007; Gender maintreaming at the World Food Programme, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Field reports: Thailand, Burma, Rwanda, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Mission to Albania and Kosovo, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Uganda, Sudan, and Colombia, 1999 (Box 7)
  - U.S. children's asylum guidelines, 1998; protection of unaccompanied refugee children (Box 7)
  - Adolescents affected by armed conflict, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Darfur and Darfur refugees in Chad, 2005-2006 (Box 7)
  - Thai-Burma border reproductive health assessment, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Colombians at risk of trafficking, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Displaced women and girls at risk, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Fuel alternatives and protection strategies, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Youth Speak Out: young people affected by armed conflict, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Education in Liberia; Firewood in Darfur, 2006 (Box 7)
  - UK Approach to Human Trafficking, 2005; UNHCR Turkey Gender and Children Team, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Care of STIs in conflict-affected settings, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Emergency contraception in conflict-affected settings, 2004 (Box 7)
  - HIV/AIDS prevention and control (facilitators manual), 2004 (Box 7)
  - Minimum Initial Service Package (MISP) for reproductive health in crisis situations, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
  - Reproductive health in refugee situations, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Masculinities, promotion of gender equality, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Iraqi refugee women and girls in Jordan, 2007 (Box 7)
  - Kosovo crisis, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Education during displacement, 2006 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and follow ups: Yugoslavia, 1992; Central America, 1992; Liberia, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and follow ups: Guinea, Ivory Coast, Ethiopia, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and recommendations: Cambodia, Ghana, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and recommendations: Afghanistan, 1990-2001 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and recommendations: Malawi, 1989-1991 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and recommendations: Laos and Thailand, 1989-1991 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports and recommendations: Hong Kong, 1989-1991 (Box 8)
  - Refugee reports for UN, experts (Box 8)
  - Refugee Experience (student handouts) (Box 8)
  - Ex-Yugoslavia reports, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Refugee women and reproductive healthcare: reassessing priorties, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Children and adolescents in Colombia, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports: Sudan, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports: Rwanda, 1994, and Liberian refugees, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Trip reports: Cambodia, 1993 (Box 8)
  - UN High Commissioner on Refugees: policy and assessment, 2002-2006 (Box 8)
  - INS treatment of unaccompanied refugee children, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Adolescents in the reconstruction of Sierra Leone, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Voting in Sierra Leone, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Gender-based violence in refugee, internally displaced, and post-conflict settings: Global Overview, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Education in Emergencies: Angola, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Reproductive health for refugees: Zambia, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Gender-based violence report; Women's Refugee Commission brochure, refugees and AIDS, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Afghan refugees, 2002-2003 (Box 8)
  - MISP fact sheets (Box 8)
  - Education in Emergencies (Box 8)
  - Trip reports: Mozambique, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Market Assessment Toolkit for vocational training providers and youth, 2008 (Box 8)
  - Halfway Home: Unaccompanied children in immigration custody, 2009 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous newsletters and factsheets, 2006-2008 (Box 9)
  - IRC and Women's Commission Advocacy Handbook (Box 9)
  - Refugee Policy adrift: U.S. and D.R. deny Haitians protection, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Disabilities among refugees and conflict-affected populations, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Locking up family values: Detention of immigrant families, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Youth and reproductive health in Northern Uganda, 2007-2008 (Box 9)
  - Reproductive health in emergencies and crisis (Box 9)
  - U.S. response to human trafficking, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Women's Refugee Commission annual reports, 1989-1998 (Box 9)
  - Women's Refugee Commission annual reports, 1999-2006; financial report, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous newsletters, press releases, and publications, 1990s-2000s (Box 9)
  - First 10 Years (Box 9)
  - Education and livelihoods in Southern Sudan, 2007-2008 (Box 9)
  - Reproductive health coordination gap (MISP) in Kenya, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Will you listen? Young voices from conflict zones, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Voices of Courage Awards invitations and programs, 1998-2009 (Box 9)
  - Economic programs for displaced populations in Nepal, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Beyond Firewood: alternative fuels and energy conference, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Monrovia/Liberia, 1992 and 2007; Iraq, Afghanistan, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Trip reports: Azerbaijan, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Guidelines for Women's Asylum Claims (Box 9)
  - Burma and the Thai border (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous brochures and publications (Box 9)
  - Building livelihoods field manual, 2009 (Box 9)
  - Newsletters, 1992-2006 (Box 9)
  - Winter newsletter, 2002; 12 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approx8mately 2 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0006, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0011)
    Includes Winter 2002 newsletter files (5 Word files and 6 photographs in jpeg file format)
  - Winter newsletter, 2002; 5 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 26 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0006, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0012)
    Includes Winter 2002 newsletter files (2 Quark files plus 3 black-and-white photographs in tiff file format). Some file formats may not be supported.
  - Women's Refugee Commission background, fact sheets (Box 9)
  - Old letterhead (Box 9)
  - Invisible Girls of War draft, 2008 (Box 10)
  - Refugee Girls: Invisible Faces of War, 2009 (Box 10)
  - Newsletters and hard print media originals (Box 10)
  - Electronic resources (Box 10)
  - Children's drawings
    - Children affected by armed conflict: Sierra Leone (artist: Marc Sommers) (Box 10)
    - Burmese and Cambodian refugees in Thailand (artist: Gail Furman) (Box 10)
    - Drawings by refugee children in Angola (artist: Gail Furman) (Box 10)
    - Refugee children drawings: Gail Furman collection (Box 10)
  - Family planning and reproductive health, 2011 and undated (Box 49)
  - Livelihood, Development and Food Security, "Cooking Fuel Saves Lives," 2011 Jan. (Box 49)
  - Parental rights and separated children, 2010-2011 and undated (Box 49)
  - "Preventing Gender-based Violence, Building Livelihoods: Guidance and Tools for Improving Programming," 2011 Dec. (Box 49)
  - Prison Rape Elimination Act (PREA) of 2003, 2011 and undated (Box 49)
  - Step-by-Step Introduction to the Market Assessment Toolkit for Vocational Training Providers, 2011 Dec. (Box 49)
  - "Tapping the Potential of Displaced Youth: Guidance for Nonformal Education and Livelihoods Development Policy and Practice," 2001 Dec. (Box 49)
  - Urban refugees reports, 2011 Mar.-Oct. (Box 49)
  - Voices of Courage awards, "Protecting and Empowring Displaced Adolescent Girls" (2012) and The Nansen Lecture program on displacement (2011) (Box 49)
  - Voices of Courage awards luncheon, "Urban Refugees," 2011 May 3 (Box 49)
  - Reports, 1989 (Box 59)
  - Reports, 1990 (Box 59)
  - Hong Kong reports, 1990 (Box 59)
  - Reports: Liberia, 1991 (Box 59)
  - Reports: Laos & Thailand, Cambodia, Vietnam, 1991 (Box 59)
  - Reports & Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 59)
  - Ethiopia & Eritrea, 1992 (Box 59)
  - Reports and Misc., 1992 (Box 59)
  - Cambodia, 1993 (Box 59)
  - Misc., 1993 (Box 59)
  - Reports, 1993 (Box 59)
  - Misc., 1994 (Box 60)
  - "Looking Toward Home: Internally Displaced Adolescents in Azerbaijan", 1998 (Box 60)
  - "The First Ten Years" WRC, 1999 (Box 60)
  - Reports, 2001 (Box 60)
  - Sierra Leone related material, 2002 (Box 60)
  - Reports, etc., 2002 (Box 60)
  - "if Not Now, When?" Addressing Gender-based Violence in Refugee/Internally Displaced, and Post-conflict Settings, 2002 (Box 60)
  - "UNHCR Policy on Refugee Women and Guidelines on Their Protection," 2002 (Box 60)
  - Varied reports, misc., 2003 (Box 60)
  - Varied reports and misc., 2006 (Box 60)
  - MISP: Indonesia, Arabic, 2007 (Box 60)
  - Various reports, 2007 (Box 60)
  - "Locking Up Family Values...", "The U.S. Response to Human Trafficking...", 2007 (Box 60)
  - "We Want Birth Control" publications, 2007 (Box 60)
  - Advocacy Handbook, 2007 (Box 60)
  - Misc. Publications, 2007 (Box 60)
  - Reports and Misc., First Ann Julia Taft Memorial Lecture, 2008 (Box 60)
  - Youth & Sustainable Livelihoods, 2008, Youth Zones, Voices from emergencies, 2007 (Box 60)
  - Market Assessment Toolkit, 2008 (Box 60)
  - "Disabilities Among Refugees and Conflict--Affected Populations": report & resource kit for fieldworkers, 2008 (Box 60)
  - Peril or Protection; Refugee Girls; INEF Guidance Notes on Teacher Compensation, 2009 (Box 60)
  - "Halfway Home: Unaccompanied Children in Immigration Custody," 2009 (Box 60)
  - Building Livelihoods: A Field Manual for Practitioners in Humanitarian Settings, 2009 (Box 60)
  - Projects for Change; Schooling & Conflict in Darfur, 2010 (Box 60)
  - Torn Apart by Immigration Enforcement, 2010 (Box 60)
  - WRC Livelihoods Manual (in French), 2010; 16 digital files extracted from an optical disc; approximately 22 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-OP-0007)
    Includes manual and resources. PDF file format
  - Uganda report, 2001; 34 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 56 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0003)
    Thirty tiff black-and-white photographs and one eps of a map. There are also two Excel tables and a file for the Uganda report. Some file formats may not be supported.
  - Uganda report, 2001; 53 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 87 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0004)
    Contains content of the report in Quark files, a PDF map, forty-two black-and-white tiff photographs and seven black-and-white tiff drawings. Some file formats may not be supported.
  - Uganda report, 2001; 14 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 50 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0005)
    Nine color photographs for cover of report in tiff file format, four Quark files of internal pages, and WCRWC logo in giff file format. Some file formats may not be supported.
  - Uganda report cover, 2001; 12 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 50 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0006)
  - Various reports, newsletters, and website materials, 2001; 107 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 63 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0007)
    Newsletter Summer 2001 (14 Word and Quark files); Resources (18 Quark files); Sexual violence guidelines (6 Quark files); Sudan maps (bmp and PDF files) and 124 photographs (tiff and jpeg files); Women's Commission files (Word and Quark files) website (6 Word files); Afghan op-ed (Word file), and Serbia report (Word file). Some file formats may not be supported.
  - AIDS brochure, 2001; 1 digital file extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 2 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0009)
    Includes WCRWC AIDS brochure, PDF file format.
  - Annual report, 2000; 1 digital file extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 6 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0013)
    Includes WC Annual report 2000 (Quark file). File format may not be supported.
  - Emergency Obstetric Care report, 2004; 6 digital files extracted from an Iomega ZIP disc; approximately 42 megabytes (Digital-materials RL01405-SET-0005, Disk RL01405-ZIP-0014)
    Includes Emergency Obstetric Care report (2 Word and 3 Quark files). File formats may not be supported.
  - Women's Refugee Commission Flickr, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - Women's Refugee Commission Blog, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - Women's Refugee Commission Website, 2011-2020; 2011-ongoing
  - Women's Refugee Commission YouTube, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - Women's Refugee Commission Twitter account, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - Women's Refugee Commission Facebook page, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
- Children, Youth, and Education Series, 3 boxes
  The Children, Youth, and Education series includes a variety of materials from that WRC program, including additional reports and guidelines. A large component consists of reports, meetings, and other files from the Education in Emergencies initiative.
  - IRC Guinea Education Program, 2005 (Box 10)
  - Against all odds: adolescents in Uganda, 2006 (Box 10)
  - Unsafe schools: Literature review of school-related gender-based violence in developing countries, 2003 (Box 10)
  - UN Handbook, 2005-2006 (Box 10)
  - Parallel worlds: Rebuilding the Education System in Kosovo, 2004 (Box 10)
  - Education in Emergencies printouts and notes (Box 10)
  - Letters from high school class on Darfur, 2006 (Box 10)
  - Education in Emergencies planning meeting, January 2001 (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Education in Emergencies meeting, Geneva, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Afghanistan report, 2003 (Box 10)
  - Population Council notes and draft, 2006 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers and notes (Box 10)
  - Internal displacement (Box 11)
  - Child refugee protection (Box 11)
  - Afghanistan conditions and refugees (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Cumberland Lodge conference: Voices Out of Conflict: Young People Affected by Forced Migration and Political Crisis, 2004 (Box 11)
  - Go Youth! project, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Education in Emergencies conference, 1999 (Box 11)
  - UNHCR/Adolescent project, 1998 (Box 11)
  - Adolescent protection, 2006 (Box 11)
  - Adolescent/child protection, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Map of programs for adolescent participation (Box 11)
  - Child protection, 2001 (Box 11)
  - Budgets, 2003-2005 (Box 11)
  - John Merck Fund, 2004 (Box 11)
  - Audits, 2003-2004 (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Violence against children, 2003-2004 (Box 11)
  - Education-related publications from NGOs and nonprofits (Box 12)
- Foundations Series, 2 boxes
  The Foundations series include name files for various foundations, trusts, and charities that support the operations of the Women's Refugee Commission. Also included are name files for former board members and commissioners.
  - Hewlett (Box 12)
  - Howard Gilman (Box 12)
  - Greenville (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Conrad Hilton (Box 12)
  - J.M. Kaplan, 1994-1999 (Box 12)
  - MacArthur (Box 12)
  - Greater New Orleans (Box 12)
  - Esther A. and Joseph Klingenstein Fund (Box 12)
  - Koerner, Fanny and Leo C.T. (Box 12)
  - John M. Lloyd Foundation (Box 12)
  - Hartford Financial Services (Box 12)
  - Global Health Award (Box 12)
  - Hauser (Box 12)
  - Hecksher Foundation for Children (Box 12)
  - Heinz (Box 12)
  - Estee Lauder Companies (Box 12)
  - Adobe Systems (Box 12)
  - Arigation Foundation (Box 12)
  - ARCA Foundation (Box 12)
  - Avon Products Foundation (Box 12)
  - Atkinson Foundation (Box 12)
  - AXA Foundation (Box 12)
  - Belle Fund (Box 12)
  - Jacob Blaustein Institute (Box 12)
  - Boehm Foundation (Box 12)
  - Bristol-Myers Squibb Foundation (Box 12)
  - Otto Bremer Foundation (Box 12)
  - Babson Foundation (Box 12)
  - California Community Foundation (Box 12)
  - Cabot Family Charitable Trust (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York (Box 12)
  - Freedom Forum (Box 12)
  - CCT (Box 13)
  - Chase Philanthropy (Box 13)
  - Centre for Women War Victims (Box 13)
  - Citigroup (Box 13)
  - Nathan Cummings Foundation (Box 13)
  - Deutsche Bank (Box 13)
  - DSI-Canada (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - General Service Foundation (Box 13)
  - Gates Global Health Award (Box 13)
  - Former Board Member name files (Box 13)
  - Commissioner name files (Box 13)
- Protection Program Series, 2 boxes
  Protection Program is a small series with materials from the Women, Peace, and Security (WPS) group and meeting files from the Commission on the Status of Women (CSW).
  - Commission on the Status of Women, 2004 (Box 13)
  - Commission on the Status of Women, 2005 and Beijing +10 (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Commission on the Status of Women, 2007 (3 folders) (Box 11 (continued from above))
  - Commission on the Status of Women Education in Emergencies panel, 2005 (Box 11 (continued from above))
  - Women, Peace, and Security gender checklist, 2003 (Box 11 (continued from above))
  - Women, Peace, and Security trainings, 2005 (Box 11 (continued from above))
  - Women, Peace, and Security: NGO working group, Sweden (Box 11 (continued from above))
- Reproductive Health Program Series, 15 boxes
  The Reproductive Health series is a large series with several subseries, all relating to the activities of the Reproductive Health program. One such subseries is the Reproductive Health Response in Conflict (RHRC) Consortium's historical documents, which includes meeting files, conference and event materials, annual reports, and some photographs. Another subseries is United States government-funded projects, covering HIV/AIDS and gender-based violence. Emergency Obstetric Care (EmOC) projects, Thai-Burma border trafficking research, donor files, and subgrantee files make up the remainder of the series.
  The majority of the Reproductive Health series is restricted, according to the wishes of the Women's Refugee Commission. The exceptions are each subseries' Summary Outputs folder consolidated in box 13B, which contains published material. Consult Research Services for information on obtaining permission to access the rest of the series.
  - Summary Outputs, 1995-2005 (Box 13B)
    Contains published material from the following subseries: Reproductive Health Response in Conflict (RHRC) Consortium, U.S. Government-funded projects (HIV/AIDS/Gender-based Violence),Emergency Obstetric Care (EmOC) Projects, Subgrants 1: Pillsbury Fund, Subgrants 2: Thailand, Subgrants 3, and Thai-Burma border research 2.
    - Summary Outputs, 1995-2005 (8 folders) (Box 13B)
  - Reproductive Health Response in Conflict (RHRC) Consortium historical documents, 1995-2005 (Box 14)
    - Proposals, 1995-2000 (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Annual meetings, 2000-2001 (Box 14)
    - Annual meetings and conferences, 1999-2000 (Box 15)
    - Advocacy Day, 2001-2002 (Box 15)
    - Conferences and projects (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Box 15)
    - Planning and training (Box 15)
    - Meetings and events, April 14-18, 1997 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Association for Women in Development Forum, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Formation of the RHRC, 1995-2000 (Box 15)
    - RHR meeting, New York, October 1994 (Box 16)
    - RHR Advocacy group meeting, 1996 (Box 16)
    - RHR meeting, New York, September 1995 (Box 16)
    - Annual reports, 1996 (Box 16)
  - U.S. Government-funded projects (HIV/AIDS/Gender-based Violence), 2000-2003
    - BPRM RHRC Consortium, Gender-based Violence projects, 2000-2001 (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - BPRM Adolescent HIV/AIDS projects, 2001-2002 (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - OFDA HIV/AIDS Southern Sudan project, October 2001-March 2003 (8 folders) (Box 17)
  - Emergency Obstetric Care (EmOC) Projects, 2000-2005 (Box 18)
    - Project files (general) (Box 18)
    - IRC: Pakistan (Box 18)
    - Maternal (Box 18)
    - IRC: Tanzania (Box 18)
    - IRC: Uganda (Box 18)
    - Mae Tao Clinic (Box 18)
    - Marie Stipes International: Kenya and Sierra Leone (Box 18)
    - ARC: Liberia (Box 18)
    - IRC: Bosnia (Box 18)
    - IRC: Liberia (Box 18)
    - Averting Maternal Death and Disability (AMDD), Columbia University (Box 18)
    - ARC: Thailand (Box 19)
    - ARC: Southern Sudan (Box 19)
    - RHRC reports (Box 19)
    - Progress reports: AMDD Among War-Affected Populations (Box 19)
    - Personnel and articles (Box 19)
    - Columbia University/Gates grants (Box 19)
    - Columbia University reports (Box 19)
    - Duplicate subgrants (Box 19)
    - Gates Foundation reports (Box 19)
    - IRC communications, Bukavu, DRC (Box 19)
    - Engender Health, Inc. (Box 19)
    - Obstetric Care Technician Advisor applications (Box 19)
  - Donor Files, 1997-2005
    - Belle Fund (Box 19)
    - Cabot Family Charitable Trust (Box 19)
    - Compton Foundation (Box 19)
    - Columbia/Packard (Box 20)
    - Najdeh (Box 20)
    - Columbia EmOC (Box 20)
    - Columbia/Packard reports (Box 20)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 20)
    - Gates (Box 20)
    - MacArthur (Box 21)
    - Mellon Foundation (Box 21)
    - Pfizer (Box 21)
    - Packard Foundation/Organizational Effectiveness and Philanthropy Program (OEP) (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Summit Foundation (Box 21)
    - Turner Foundation (Box 21)
    - UNFPA (4 folders) (Box 21)
    - UNFPA (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - UNHCR (Box 22)
  - Subgrants 1: Pillsbury Fund, 2000-2003
    Pillsbury Fund grants for adolescent reproductive health projects.
    - ARC: Southern Sudan (Box 22)
    - Afghan Women's Resource Center (Box 22)
    - ANGOBEFA: Angola (Box 22)
    - ARHANG: Thailand (Box 22)
    - Bhutanese women and Nepal youth empowerment program (Box 22)
    - CARE: Somalia (Box 22)
    - CEM: Sierra Leone (Box 22)
    - CCYA: Sierra Leone (Box 22)
    - CORD: Zambia (Box 22)
    - CPA: Uganda (Box 22)
    - DOW: Thailand (Box 22)
    - EVAS: Goma, DRC (Box 22)
    - FAWE: Sierra Leone (Box 23)
    - FPHC: Pakistan (Box 23)
    - GLAP: Goma, DRC (Box 23)
    - GYFA: Uganda (Box 23)
    - HODI (Box 23)
    - IACRC: Burundi (Box 23)
    - IRC: Liberia (Box 23)
    - LPAPA: Ethiopia (Box 23)
    - Mae Tao Clinic: Thailand (Box 23)
    - MSI: Angola (Box 23)
    - Naomi Nyitambe (Box 23)
    - NUEYS: Eritrea (Box 23)
    - Profamilia: Colombia (Box 23)
    - ARC: Sudan (Box 23)
    - Rakhaing Women's Union (RWU): Bangladesh (Box 23)
    - RHG: Liberia (Box 23)
    - SAW: Thailand (Box 23)
    - Shuhada: Afghanistan (Box 23)
    - Tamer: Gaza (Box 23)
    - Tan Ux'il: Guatemala (Box 23)
    - UMATI: Tanzania (Box 23)
    - WATWERO: Uganda (Box 23)
    - Women's Wellness Center: Kosovo (Box 23)
    - World Vision: Zambia (Box 23)
  - Subgrants 2: Thailand, 1998-2005
    - Mae Tao Clinic (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - Social Action for Women (6 folders) (Box 24)
  - ANGOBEFA pictures and brochures (Box 24)
  - Subgrants 3
    - Association Najdeh (5 folders) (Box 24)
  - Inter-agency Working Group (IAWG) on Reproductive Health in Crises documents, 1997-2003 (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Thai-Burma border research 1: 2003 trafficking report, 1990-2003 (Box 25)
    - Thai-Burma resources (Box 25)
    - 2003 report resources (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - 2003 research (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - 2003 research (3 folders) (Box 26)
    - 2003 report-other sources (Box 26)
  - Thai-Burma border research 2: 2004 report and annotated bibliography, 2000-2006
    - Camp research (3 folders) (Box 26)
    - Migrant research (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - Migrant research (5) (Box 27)
    - General research (3 folders) (Box 27)
- Media Series, 2 boxes
  The Media series consists of newspaper clippings and printouts regarding refugee sitations and news coverage of the Women's Refugee Commission.
  - Media binders, February 1989-March 2004 (Box 28)
  - Media binders, April 2004-December 2008 (Box 29)
- Social Protection and Livelihoods Unit Series, 5 boxes
  The Livelihoods series includes materials from various projects and iniatives, including the AGDM program, strategic planning, trafficking, and youth programs, as well as projects with Fordham, SIPA at Columbia University, Nike, and Reebok. Also contains board delegation visits to Liberia, Thailand, Nepal, and Colombia, as well as conference and classroom participation materials.